<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>avisvascular@gmail.com &#8211; Avis-Hospitals</title>
	<atom:link href="/author/avisvasculargmail-com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 03:42:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Innovative Technologies in Vein Care: From CLACS to Medical Glue</title>
		<link>/innovative-technologies-in-vein-care-from-clacs-to-medical-glue/</link>
					<comments>/innovative-technologies-in-vein-care-from-clacs-to-medical-glue/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[avisvascular@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 03:42:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=14811</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The landscape of vein care has seen remarkable advancements over the past decade, transitioning from traditional surgical methods to innovative, minimally invasive treatments. This shift not only enhances patient outcomes but also reduces recovery times and associated risks. Two prominent treatments leading this transformation are Cryo Laser and Cryo Sclerotherapy ...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="740" height="430" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/after11.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-14408"/></figure></div>


<p>The landscape of vein care has seen remarkable advancements over the past decade, transitioning from traditional surgical methods to innovative, minimally invasive treatments. This shift not only enhances patient outcomes but also reduces recovery times and associated risks. Two prominent treatments leading this transformation are Cryo Laser and Cryo Sclerotherapy (CLACS) and VenaSeal. This blog delves into these cutting-edge treatments and highlights their benefits over traditional vein surgery.</p>



<p><strong>Traditional Vein Surgery: A Brief Overview</strong></p>



<p>Traditionally, vein diseases such as varicose veins were treated using vein stripping and ligation. This surgical procedure involves making small incisions along the vein and physically removing or tying off the affected veins. While effective, vein stripping comes with several drawbacks:</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Invasiveness</strong>: The procedure is surgical, requiring anesthesia and multiple incisions.</li>



<li><strong>Recovery Time</strong>: Patients often face lengthy recovery periods, with significant bruising and discomfort.</li>



<li><strong>Risks</strong>: There is a higher risk of complications, including infections, scarring, and nerve damage.</li>
</ol>



<p>Given these challenges, the medical community has sought less invasive alternatives to enhance patient comfort and outcomes.</p>



<p><strong>CLACS: A Hybrid Approach</strong></p>



<p>Cryo Laser and Cryo Sclerotherapy (CLACS) is a hybrid treatment combining laser therapy and sclerotherapy with the added benefit of cooling to minimize discomfort. Developed by Brazilian dermatologist Dr. Kasuo Miyake, CLACS offers several advantages:</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Minimally Invasive</strong>: Unlike traditional surgery, CLACS requires no incisions. Instead, it uses laser energy to target the vein and sclerotherapy to close it off.</li>



<li><strong>Reduced Pain</strong>: The cooling aspect of CLACS significantly reduces pain and discomfort during the procedure.</li>



<li><strong>Quick Recovery</strong>: Patients can typically resume normal activities within a day or two, with minimal downtime.</li>



<li><strong>Cosmetic Benefits</strong>: The absence of surgical incisions means no scarring, making it an aesthetically appealing option.</li>
</ol>



<p><strong>VenaSeal: A Revolutionary Adhesive</strong></p>



<p>VenaSeal is another groundbreaking treatment that utilizes a medical adhesive to close off varicose veins. The procedure involves the insertion of a catheter into the affected vein, through which the adhesive is delivered. VenaSeal offers several key benefits:</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Non-Thermal and Non-Tumescent</strong>: Unlike laser or radiofrequency treatments that require heat and anesthesia, VenaSeal is performed without the need for tumescent anesthesia, making it virtually painless.</li>



<li><strong>Immediate Results</strong>: The adhesive works quickly to seal the vein, providing immediate relief from symptoms.</li>



<li><strong>No Compression Stockings</strong>: Post-procedure care does not require wearing compression stockings, which can be uncomfortable and inconvenient for patients.</li>



<li><strong>Minimal Downtime</strong>: Patients can return to their daily activities almost immediately, with no significant recovery period.</li>
</ol>



<p><strong>Benefits of Minimally Invasive Treatments Over Traditional Surgery</strong></p>



<p><strong>1. Lower Risk of Complications</strong></p>



<p>Minimally invasive treatments like CLACS and VenaSeal significantly reduce the risk of complications compared to traditional vein surgery. The absence of large incisions minimizes the risk of infections, scarring, and nerve damage. Additionally, these procedures are often performed under local anesthesia, further lowering the risk associated with general anesthesia.</p>



<p><strong>2. Enhanced Patient Comfort</strong></p>



<p>The patient experience is vastly improved with minimally invasive treatments. Procedures like CLACS incorporate cooling techniques to reduce pain, and VenaSeal’s non-thermal approach eliminates the discomfort associated with heat-based treatments. Patients often report minimal pain and a high level of satisfaction with these modern techniques.</p>



<p><strong>3. Faster Recovery Times</strong></p>



<p>One of the most significant advantages of these innovative treatments is the rapid recovery time. Traditional vein surgery can require weeks of downtime, while minimally invasive options typically allow patients to resume normal activities within a day or two. This quick return to daily life is a major benefit for those with busy schedules or demanding lifestyles.</p>



<p><strong>4. Improved Cosmetic Outcomes</strong></p>



<p>For many patients, the cosmetic outcome is a crucial consideration. Traditional vein surgery often leaves noticeable scars, whereas minimally invasive treatments like CLACS and VenaSeal leave little to no scarring. This aspect is particularly important for individuals concerned about the aesthetic appearance of their legs.</p>



<p>As technology continues to advance, patients can look forward to even more effective and less invasive options for managing venous diseases, ultimately leading to better overall health and quality of life. At Avis Vascular Center which is at the forefront of vein care, we offer advanced treatments like CLACS and VenaSeal that provide significant advantages over traditional surgical methods. Call today to book an appointment.</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/innovative-technologies-in-vein-care-from-clacs-to-medical-glue/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why is EVLT the Best Treatment for Varicose Veins?</title>
		<link>/why-is-evlt-the-best-treatment-for-varicose-veins/</link>
					<comments>/why-is-evlt-the-best-treatment-for-varicose-veins/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[avisvascular@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 03:46:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[EVLT]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/avis-vascular/?p=14603</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Veins are a network of blood vessels that carry deoxygenated blood back to the heart. And all the veins in the body have valves. These valves ensure that your blood continues to flow towards the heart, and not in the opposite direction.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="14603" class="elementor elementor-14603">
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-2a0c9577 e-flex e-con-boxed e-con e-parent" data-id="2a0c9577" data-element_type="container">
					<div class="e-con-inner">
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-239bbaf3 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="239bbaf3" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
									
<h4 class="wp-block-heading"> </h4>

<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="1600" height="1067" class="wp-image-14242" src="http://localhost/avis-vascular/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/1600X1067-1.png" alt="" /></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-center">Veins are a network of blood vessels that carry deoxygenated blood back to the heart. And all the veins in the body have valves. These valves ensure that your blood continues to flow towards the heart, and not in the opposite direction.</p>

<p><strong>However, in </strong><a href="https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/andhra-pradesh/varicose-veins-prevalent-in-30-indians-says-expert/article66877215.ece" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>up to 30% of the Indian population</strong></a><strong>, these valves get damaged, turning the healthy veins into varicose veins.</strong></p>

<p>Because of varicose veins, over 40 crore Indians experience symptoms like leg irritation, swelling and ulcers!</p>

<p>The good news is, modern medicine provides a minimally invasive solution to varicose veins in the form of Endovenous Laser Therapy.</p>

<p>In this blog, we will explore the devastating effects of varicose veins and what makes EVLT one of the best varicose veins treatments available. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Signs of Varicose Veins and Why They Appear</h2>

<p>Varicose veins develop in stages, but once this disease develops, it continues growing until it is treated. The symptoms are mild in the early stages, ranging from pain in the legs to itching or burning sensations and leg cramps at night.</p>

<p>These symptoms are so common in the Indian population – especially in Indian women – that they think these symptoms are normal!</p>

<p>Most Indians believe that bulging veins and burning sensations are “just what happens” if you’re on your feet for too long.</p>

<p>But when you feel any of the varicose veins symptoms, there are two things happening to your body in that moment:</p>

<p>1. There is a high amount of pressure inside your veins, and</p>

<p>2. The excess pressure is actively damaging your healthy veins.</p>

<p>If you keep ignoring these signs and don’t take the right steps to maintain your vascular health, more severe symptoms will develop, such as:</p>

<p>· Swelling</p>

<p>· Vein bursts</p>

<p>· Skin changes (darkening of the legs)</p>

<p>· Painful ulcers</p>

<p>· Infections</p>

<p>· Blood clots</p>

<p>The earlier you seek treatment for varicose veins, the better it will be for your long-term health. If you’re experiencing any of the symptoms, consult India’s best varicose veins specialist, Dr. Rajah Koppala, at Avis Hospitals.</p>

<p>With 40,000+ happy patients and a success rate exceeding 98%, Dr. Koppala is one of the top varicose veins specialists in the world.</p>

<p>Remember: </p>

<p>Vein damage is permanent. No doctor or treatment can reverse the damage done to broken and damaged vein valves and walls.</p>

<p>However, you <em>can</em> get relief from symptoms and protect your healthy veins with the advanced varicose vein procedures at Avis Vascular Centre.</p>

<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What Causes Varicose Veins?</strong></h3>

<p>The commonest reason for varicose veins is genetics.</p>

<p>In fact, a <a href="https://www.ahajournals.org/doi/10.1161/CIRCGENETICS.112.963439" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">research article</a> published in the <em>American Heart Association Journals</em> in 2014 stated that patients have a 90% risk of developing varicose veins if the parents had it.</p>

<p>But genetics are not the only culprit. Hormonal changes (due to medications or otherwise), pregnancy, sedentary lifestyles, standing for long periods, obesity and old age also cause damaged veins.</p>

<p>When a healthy vein becomes a varicose vein because of any of these reasons, it begins a disastrous cycle for your circulatory system.</p>

<p>Since the damaged valves in the varicosed vein no longer prevent the blood from flowing downwards, the valves in the healthy veins must bear the additional pressure.</p>

<p>Eventually, the pressure builds up to a point where the healthy valves also become damaged and varicosed. This is why varicose veins is a progressive disease – it keeps getting worse after developing.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What is Endovenous Laser Ablation?</h2>

<p>The Endovenous Laser Therapy (EVLT) is a one of the most popular minimally invasive varicose vein treatments. It is also called the Endovenous Laser Ablation for varicose veins.</p>

<p>The procedure does not involve any cutting or stitching and is usually performed by an interventional radiologist. The operation begins by administering local anaesthesia to the patient.</p>

<p>Then, the varicose vein doctor inserts a catheter, which is like a thin wire, in a spot that makes it easy to access the damaged veins. It may be inserted around the knee or thigh, depending on where the varicose veins are situated.</p>

<p>The entire procedure is done under ultrasound guidance, and the doctor guides the catheter into the targeted varicose veins. When the catheter is appropriately placed, the laser at the tip of the catheter is activated, and the catheter is slowly pulled out.</p>

<p>The laser heats up and seals the damaged vein shut without damaging the skin or muscles. This process causes little to no pain and takes no longer than an hour. The patient is monitored for a few hours after the treatment, and can return home later in the day.</p>

<p>Since the blood no longer flows from the faulty veins, the patient experiences relief from the symptoms!</p>

<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What Makes EVLT the Best Varicose Veins Treatment?</strong></h3>

<p>There are many reasons why EVLT is considered an excellent treatment option for varicose veins.</p>

<p>Doctors all over the world adopted this treatment soon after it was made available. These days, traditional surgery for varicose veins is only required in rare cases where there is no other alternative.</p>

<p>The advantages of EVLT include:</p>

<p>· High success rates</p>

<p>· Short procedure (1 hour maximum)</p>

<p>· Same-day discharge</p>

<p>· No scarring</p>

<p>· Quick relief from symptoms</p>

<p>· Better results than open surgery</p>

<p>· Affordable operation</p>

<p>· Minimal pain and discomfort during recovery</p>

<p>· Low risk of complications</p>

<p>· Can return to regular routine from next day</p>

<p>· Suitable for patients with BP problems or diabetes</p>

<h3 class="wp-block-heading">What Happens After the EVLT Procedure</h3>

<p>When the procedure is over, you will be asked to walk for 30 minutes or more. You may see minor bruising on your legs after the treatment, but it will disappear in about two weeks.</p>

<p>Note that you will need to be driven home, and you cannot drive right after the treatment.</p>

<p>Patients are usually asked to wear compression stockings daily until the follow-up consultation. At Avis Hospitals, patients are asked to visit the doctor 10 days after the treatment.</p>

<p>Further use of compression stockings may be recommended depending on how well the patient is recovering. Our varicose veins experts also recommend limiting salt intake, exercising daily and reducing weight (if the patient is obese) after the procedure.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Conclusion: Take Your First Step Towards Varicose Veins Recovery</h2>

<p>Varicose veins is a common and often overlooked health problem that can cause a patient a lot of pain and trouble.</p>

<p>If you are experiencing the symptoms of varicose veins and are considering treatment, make sure you consult a correctly qualified and highly-experienced doctor.</p>

<p>Avis Hospitals has a track record of over 40,000 happy patients and was named India’s best varicose veins hospital by Times Network at the India Health Awards 2024.</p>

<p>For complete relief from the most experienced specialists anywhere in India, book your appointment at Avis Hospitals today. </p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Dr. Rajah V Koppala</h4>

<p> </p>
								</div>
				</div>
					</div>
				</div>
		<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-ce67ac7 e-flex e-con-boxed e-con e-parent" data-id="ce67ac7" data-element_type="container">
					<div class="e-con-inner">
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-dc34de6 elementor-widget__width-initial elementor-fixed elementor-shape-rounded elementor-grid-0 e-grid-align-center elementor-widget elementor-widget-social-icons" data-id="dc34de6" data-element_type="widget" data-settings="{&quot;_position&quot;:&quot;fixed&quot;}" data-widget_type="social-icons.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<div class="elementor-social-icons-wrapper elementor-grid">
							<span class="elementor-grid-item">
					<a class="elementor-icon elementor-social-icon elementor-social-icon-facebook elementor-animation-bounce-in elementor-repeater-item-7d15a07" target="_blank">
						<span class="elementor-screen-only">Facebook</span>
						<svg class="e-font-icon-svg e-fab-facebook" viewBox="0 0 512 512" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><path d="M504 256C504 119 393 8 256 8S8 119 8 256c0 123.78 90.69 226.38 209.25 245V327.69h-63V256h63v-54.64c0-62.15 37-96.48 93.67-96.48 27.14 0 55.52 4.84 55.52 4.84v61h-31.28c-30.8 0-40.41 19.12-40.41 38.73V256h68.78l-11 71.69h-57.78V501C413.31 482.38 504 379.78 504 256z"></path></svg>					</a>
				</span>
							<span class="elementor-grid-item">
					<a class="elementor-icon elementor-social-icon elementor-social-icon-twitter elementor-animation-bounce-in elementor-repeater-item-3991bd2" target="_blank">
						<span class="elementor-screen-only">Twitter</span>
						<svg class="e-font-icon-svg e-fab-twitter" viewBox="0 0 512 512" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><path d="M459.37 151.716c.325 4.548.325 9.097.325 13.645 0 138.72-105.583 298.558-298.558 298.558-59.452 0-114.68-17.219-161.137-47.106 8.447.974 16.568 1.299 25.34 1.299 49.055 0 94.213-16.568 130.274-44.832-46.132-.975-84.792-31.188-98.112-72.772 6.498.974 12.995 1.624 19.818 1.624 9.421 0 18.843-1.3 27.614-3.573-48.081-9.747-84.143-51.98-84.143-102.985v-1.299c13.969 7.797 30.214 12.67 47.431 13.319-28.264-18.843-46.781-51.005-46.781-87.391 0-19.492 5.197-37.36 14.294-52.954 51.655 63.675 129.3 105.258 216.365 109.807-1.624-7.797-2.599-15.918-2.599-24.04 0-57.828 46.782-104.934 104.934-104.934 30.213 0 57.502 12.67 76.67 33.137 23.715-4.548 46.456-13.32 66.599-25.34-7.798 24.366-24.366 44.833-46.132 57.827 21.117-2.273 41.584-8.122 60.426-16.243-14.292 20.791-32.161 39.308-52.628 54.253z"></path></svg>					</a>
				</span>
							<span class="elementor-grid-item">
					<a class="elementor-icon elementor-social-icon elementor-social-icon-youtube elementor-animation-bounce-in elementor-repeater-item-579d882" target="_blank">
						<span class="elementor-screen-only">Youtube</span>
						<svg class="e-font-icon-svg e-fab-youtube" viewBox="0 0 576 512" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><path d="M549.655 124.083c-6.281-23.65-24.787-42.276-48.284-48.597C458.781 64 288 64 288 64S117.22 64 74.629 75.486c-23.497 6.322-42.003 24.947-48.284 48.597-11.412 42.867-11.412 132.305-11.412 132.305s0 89.438 11.412 132.305c6.281 23.65 24.787 41.5 48.284 47.821C117.22 448 288 448 288 448s170.78 0 213.371-11.486c23.497-6.321 42.003-24.171 48.284-47.821 11.412-42.867 11.412-132.305 11.412-132.305s0-89.438-11.412-132.305zm-317.51 213.508V175.185l142.739 81.205-142.739 81.201z"></path></svg>					</a>
				</span>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
					</div>
				</div>
		<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-05969b4 e-flex e-con-boxed e-con e-parent" data-id="05969b4" data-element_type="container">
					<div class="e-con-inner">
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-9a15470 elementor-widget elementor-widget-image" data-id="9a15470" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
															<img decoding="async" width="640" height="372" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/after11.jpg" class="attachment-large size-large wp-image-14408" alt="" />															</div>
				</div>
					</div>
				</div>
				</div>
		]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/why-is-evlt-the-best-treatment-for-varicose-veins/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
