<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Services &#8211; Avis-Hospitals</title>
	<atom:link href="/fw-service/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 07:30:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Varicocele Treatment</title>
		<link>/fw-service/varicocele-treatment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[avisvascular@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 03:08:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=fw-service#038;p=14764</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Varicocele Treatment is done for men, especially in adolescents and young adults. The treatment helps to manage varicoceles (enlarged and twisted veins within the scrotum) that can affect sperm production and male fertility. Varicocele Treatment is recommended when varicoceles causes’ persistent pain, male infertility arises due to prolonged varicoceles condition ...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Varicocele Treatment is done for men, especially in adolescents and young adults. The treatment helps to manage varicoceles (enlarged and twisted veins within the scrotum) that can affect sperm production and male fertility. Varicocele Treatment is recommended when varicoceles causes’ persistent pain, male infertility arises due to prolonged varicoceles condition and in some cases of varicoceles leading to testicular atrophy (shrinkage).</p>
<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14803" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Varicocele-Treatment-copy.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="697" /></p>
<p><strong>Effectiveness of Varicocele Treatment and its applications</strong></p>
<p>Varicocele Treatment is quite effective in improving fertility in men with varicocele-related infertility. The treatment is applicable as it has lower rate of complications and faster recovery compared to surgery. Varicocele Treatment helps to alleviate pain with nonsurgical  treatments (like embolization) that are effective at relieving discomfort caused by varicoceles in most cases.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Thyroid Nodule Embolization</title>
		<link>/fw-service/thyroid-nodule-embolization/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[avisvascular@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 03:04:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=fw-service#038;p=14763</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Thyroid Nodule Embolization is a medical procedure used to treat conditions that result from excessive production of thyroid hormones such as thyroid nodules and hyperthyroidism. In this technique the arteries providing blood to thyroid gland are embolized (blocked) to ensure that hyperactive of thyroid gland is checked. It is a ...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thyroid Nodule Embolization is a medical procedure used to treat conditions that result from excessive production of thyroid hormones such as thyroid nodules and hyperthyroidism. In this technique the arteries providing blood to thyroid gland are embolized (blocked) to ensure that hyperactive of thyroid gland is checked. It is a minimal invasive method to manage hyperthyroidism without the need for surgery.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14802" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Thyroid-Nodule-copy.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="697" /></p>
<p><strong>Effectiveness of Thyroid Nodule Embolization and its applications</strong><br />
Thyroid Nodule Embolization is quite effective and safe method with minimally invasive procedure, sustains thyroid functioning to some extent, no scars and quick recovery &#8211; same day discharge option. Thyroid Nodule Embolization has unique applications for elderly patients unable to tolerate stress of traditional surgery and patients with significant comorbidities such as heart disease, obesity, or diabetes risky to surgical treatments.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fibroids Treatment</title>
		<link>/fw-service/fibroids-treatment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[avisvascular@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 02:39:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=fw-service#038;p=14756</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fibroids Treatment (Uterine fibroids treatment) is done by multiple ways of medical, surgical (minimally invasive procedures, and surgical interventions, such as myomectomy or hysterectomy, etc.), and therapeutic approaches in order to manage and alleviate the symptoms of uterine fibroids-non-cancerous growths that develop in or around the uterus. The treatment focuses ...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Fibroids Treatment (Uterine fibroids treatment) is done by multiple ways of medical, surgical (minimally invasive procedures, and surgical interventions, such as myomectomy or hysterectomy, etc.), and therapeutic approaches in order to manage and alleviate the symptoms of uterine fibroids-non-cancerous growths that develop in or around the uterus. The treatment focuses to alleviate symptoms such as heavy menstrual bleeding, pelvic pain, bloating, and urinary issues. The treatment process varies in accordance patient’s age, fertility goals, and overall health.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14801" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Fibroids-Treatment-copy.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="697" /></p>
<p><strong>Effectiveness of Fibroids Treatment and its applications</strong><br />
The effectiveness of Fibroids Treatment is dependent on a certain factors such as age, fertility goals, overall health, and symptom severity which is needed to consulted with health care professionals. This treatment is applied with proper medications, minimally invasive procedures, along with consideration of the patient’s fertility desires, and lifestyle changes pattern.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lymphedema Therapy</title>
		<link>/fw-service/lymphedema-therapy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[avisvascular@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 02:25:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=fw-service#038;p=14754</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Lymphedema Therapy targets to manage and treat the symptoms of lymphedema, a condition characterized by the abnormal accumulation of lymphatic fluid, leading to swelling, typically in the arms or legs. Lymphedema Therapy focuses to reduce swelling, improve lymphatic drainage, prevent complications (such as infections or tissue damage), and enhance the ...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lymphedema Therapy targets to manage and treat the symptoms of lymphedema, a condition characterized by the abnormal accumulation of lymphatic fluid, leading to swelling, typically in the arms or legs. Lymphedema Therapy focuses to reduce swelling, improve lymphatic drainage, prevent complications (such as infections or tissue damage), and enhance the patient’s quality of life.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14800" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Lymphedema-Therapy-copy.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="697" /></p>
<p><strong>Effectiveness of Lymphedema Therapy and its applications</strong><br />
Lymphedema Therapy is an effective treatment for targeting in reduction of swelling through manual lymphatic drainage (MLD) and compression therapy. Lymphedema Therapy is applicable by a good coordination between both the physical symptoms and psychosocial impacts of lymphedema, thereby significantly improvement in patient outcomes, limited burden of chronic swelling, and help individuals to slow the progression of the disease.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cryo Laser and Cryo Sclerotherapy (CLaCS):</title>
		<link>/fw-service/cryo-laser-and-cryo-sclerotherapy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[avisvascular@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 02:17:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=fw-service#038;p=14753</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Leg Ulcer Management refers to an integrated approach in treatment and caring for leg ulcers, which are open sores or wounds that typically occur on the lower legs and canMenus be slow to heal. With proper Leg Ulcer Management it can provide a good way of diagnosing, treating, and caring ...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Leg Ulcer Management refers to an integrated approach in treatment and caring for leg ulcers, which are open sores or wounds that typically occur on the lower legs and can<a href="/wp-admin/nav-menus.php">Menus</a> be slow to heal. With proper Leg Ulcer Management it can provide a good way of diagnosing, treating, and caring for leg ulcers and improve the patient&amp;#39;s quality of life. Leg Ulcer Management involves healthcare professionals like wound care specialists, vascular surgeons, and sometimes physical therapists for the best treatment.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14799" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Leg-Ulcer-Management-copy.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="697" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Effectiveness of Leg Ulcer Management and its applications:</strong><br />
Leg Ulcer Management is very much effective and a comprehensive approach for addressing any contributing health conditions, such as poor circulation, diabetes, or venous insufficiency. Leg Ulcer Management has got multidisciplinary applications in wound care, compression therapy, infection control, pain management, surgical interventions, patient education for lifestyle modifications and along with psychological &#8211; overall supportive care for treatment of patients.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stab Phlebectomy:</title>
		<link>/fw-service/stab-phlebectomy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[avisvascular@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 06:29:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=fw-service#038;p=14736</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Stab Phlebectomy is procedure that removes varicose veins by minimally-invasive method. In this method tiny cuts are made on the skin and varicose veins are removed.This procedure involves making tiny punctures or incisions through which the varicose veins areremoved with use of local anesthesia. Effectiveness of Stab Phlebectomy and its ...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Stab Phlebectomy is procedure that removes varicose veins by minimally-invasive method. In this method tiny cuts are made on the skin and varicose veins are removed.This procedure involves making tiny punctures or incisions through which the varicose veins areremoved with use of local anesthesia.<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14737" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Stab-Phlebectomy-copy.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="697" /></p>
<p><strong>Effectiveness of Stab Phlebectomy and its applications</strong><br />
Stab Phlebectomy is effective for removal of surface varicose veins, with fewer incisions scarring is minimal, recovery time is typically short and long term results. Stab Phlebectomy is applied for particularly large or bulging veins that are difficult to address with other methods and it carries fewer risks than traditional vein stripping surgery.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Leg Ulcer Management(LUM)</title>
		<link>/fw-service/leg-ulcer-management-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[avisvascular@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 06:22:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=fw-service#038;p=14734</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Leg Ulcer Management refers to an integrated approach in treatment and caring for leg ulcers, which are open sores or wounds that typically occur on the lower legs and canMenus be slow to heal. With proper Leg Ulcer Management it can provide a good way of diagnosing, treating, and caring for ...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Leg Ulcer Management refers to an integrated approach in treatment and caring for leg ulcers, which are open sores or wounds that typically occur on the lower legs and can<a href="/wp-admin/nav-menus.php">Menus</a> be slow to heal. With proper Leg Ulcer Management it can provide a good way of diagnosing, treating, and caring for leg ulcers and improve the patient&amp;#39;s quality of life. Leg Ulcer Management involves healthcare professionals like wound care specialists, vascular surgeons, and sometimes physical therapists for the best treatment.</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone wp-image-14799 size-full" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Leg-Ulcer-Management-copy.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="697" /></p>
<p><strong>Effectiveness of Leg Ulcer Management and its applications:</strong><br />
<strong>Leg Ulcer Management is very much effective and a comprehensive approach for addressing any contributing health conditions, such as poor circulation, diabetes, or venous insufficiency. Leg Ulcer Management has got multidisciplinary applications in wound care, compression therapy, infection control, pain management, surgical interventions, patient education for lifestyle modifications and along with psychological – overall supportive care for treatment of patients.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Endovenous Laser Ablation Therapy(EVLA)</title>
		<link>/fw-service/endovenous-laser-ablation-therapy-evla/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[avisvascular@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 06:07:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=fw-service#038;p=14733</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Endovenous Laser Ablation Therapy (EVLA) is a procedure that helps to close varicose veins, restarting circulation and removing twisted part ultimately the bulging veins to regain normalcy. Endovenous Laser Ablation(EVLA) is a minimally invasive medical treatment procedure used to treat varicose veins and it is done with the help of ...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Endovenous Laser Ablation Therapy (EVLA) is a procedure that helps to close varicose veins, restarting circulation and removing twisted part ultimately the bulging veins to regain normalcy. Endovenous Laser Ablation(EVLA) is a minimally invasive medical treatment procedure used to treat varicose veins and it is done with the help of laser energy use through catheter.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14739" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Endovenous-Laser-Ablation-copy.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="697" /></p>
<p><strong>Effectiveness of EVLA and its applications</strong></p>
<p>EVLA is very effective as it has the same day discharge treatment procedure for outpatient. Quick recovery and minimal invasive procedure is added feature of EVLA. EVLA has several applications such as varicose veins treatment, helps to improve blood flow in legs and reduce the risk of leg ulcer formation and in some cases of Post-Thrombotic Syndrome (PTS) usually arised after deep vein thrombosis (DVT) are also treated by this method.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Radio Frequency Ablation (RFA)</title>
		<link>/fw-service/radio-frequency-ablation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[avisvascular@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 05:59:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=fw-service#038;p=14731</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Radio Frequency Ablation (RFA) is a minimally invasive procedure adopted to treat varicose veins. This procedure is performed to avoid pain and follow nonsurgical technique with application of radiofrequency energy for generating heat. The heat is sent into the vein through a thin, flexible tube (catheter). This closes off blood ...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Radio Frequency Ablation (RFA) is a minimally invasive procedure adopted to treat varicose veins. This procedure is performed to avoid pain and follow nonsurgical technique with application of radiofrequency energy for generating heat. The heat is sent into the vein through a thin, flexible tube (catheter). This closes off blood flow in the main problem vein.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14740" src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Radio-Frequency-Ablation-RFA-.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="697" /></p>
<p><strong>Effectiveness of RFA and its applications</strong></p>
<p>RFA is a very effective procedure for targeted treatment towards specific abnormal tissue, with relatively low risk of complications such as bleeding, infection and damage to nearby tissue or organ. RFA has got applications especially for treating varicose veins, shrinking of benign thyroid nodules, and certain cases of endometriosis with difficult location-to-reach areas.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
